{
    "id": "973454eb25a849abb8cb2c3ca47d6a10",
    "title": "Relative Pronouns Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I help those ………………………. I love.",
            "description": "When the relative pronoun is the object of the relative clause we use whom.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "that"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He …………………….. works hard will certainly succeed.",
            "description": "We use who to refer to people.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which",
                ""
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The man ……………………………. has no music in his soul should be tried for treason.",
            "description": "In identifying relative clauses, both who and that can refer to people.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I have received the message …………………………. you sent me.",
            "description": "That and which can both refer to things.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "which",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Servants …………………………. are honest are trusted.",
            "description": "In identifying relative clauses, both who and that can refer to people.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He failed in every project ………………………… he started.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "which",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He laughs best …………………………. laughs last.",
            "description": "When the relative pronoun is the subject of the relative clause we use who to refer to people. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "They never fail ……………………………. die for a good cause.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He …………………………. is down need fear no fall.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "This is the bicycle …………………………. I bought for my son.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "which",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He is an accomplished singer ………………………. I admire.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I know a man ………………………….. son is an activist.",
            "description": "The relative pronoun whose replaces the personal pronouns his, her or their.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "who's",
                "whose"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}